<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on YoungHom</title>
    <link>https://younghomseminar.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on YoungHom</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright> </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://younghomseminar.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Global homotopy theory via lax limits</title>
      <link>https://younghomseminar.github.io/posts/11-10-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://younghomseminar.github.io/posts/11-10-2022/</guid>
      <description>Speaker: Sil Linskens - University of Bonn
Abstract: Global equivariant stable homotopy theory is a formalism which admits applications to orbifold cohomology, elliptic cohomology and importantly equivariant stable homotopy theory. Many important equivariant spectra admit global refinements, and these refinements have led to theoretical advances and have aided in calculations. However not only does global homotopy theory admit applications to equivariant homotopy theory, but it seems reasonable to expect that global homotopy theory is in some sense determined by equivariant homotopy theory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dimensions of colimits</title>
      <link>https://younghomseminar.github.io/posts/09-15-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://younghomseminar.github.io/posts/09-15-2022/</guid>
      <description>Speaker: Maxime Ramzi – Unversity of Copenhagen
Abstract: We use the Hochschild-homological interpretation of dimensions and more generally traces in symmetric monoidal $\infty$-categories to produce formulas for dimensions and traces of colimits over sufficiently nice spaces.
These formulas specialize on the one hand to the very classical character-theoretic formulas for dimensions of coinvariants in the case of vector spaces in characteristic $0$ and when the space is $BG$ for some finite group $G$; and on the other hand to the Blumberg-Cohen-Schlichtkrull formula for topological Hochschild homology of Thom spectra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polygons and TR with coefficients</title>
      <link>https://younghomseminar.github.io/posts/09-01-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://younghomseminar.github.io/posts/09-01-2022/</guid>
      <description>Speaker: Jonas McCandless - University of Münster
Abstract: I will introduce the notion of a polygonic spectrum which is a multi-object version of the notion of a cyclotomic spectrum indexed by polygons rather than the circle. This is designed to capture the structure on topological Hochschild homology of a ring with coefficients in a bimodule. Using this, I will explain the construction of TR with coefficients and explain how this is equipped with compatible Frobenius and Verschiebung maps.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
